PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(introductory sound)
（过门）
We saw in the previous lesson
从前面的课程中我们了解到
that to write a ray tracer,
要写一个光线追踪渲染器
you need a mathematical way
你需要一个数学手段
to answer a bunch of questions.
来回答一系列问题
Where does a ray intersect a scene object?
射线在何处与场景物体相交？
Does a shadow ray reach the light source
一束阴影射线在与另一个物体相交前
before it intersects another object?
是否就已经到达了光源？
How does the surface reflect light?
物体的面时如何反射光的？
How far away is the light source?
光源距离多远？
Finally, where is the camera?
最后是 摄像机在什么位置？
In the remainder of this lesson,
在余下的课程中
we're going to focus on the first sub-problem,
我们将集火第一个小问题
that of ray object intersection.
也就是射线-物体相交
We're going to start our study
我们将从一个简化的问题
by first looking at the simpler problem
开始我们的学习
of how to do ray object intersection
在二维中 射线-物体相交
in two dimensions.
该如何实现
What does ray tracing look like in two dimensions?
光线追踪在二维中看起来是什么样的？
Let's start with our three-dimensional situation
让我们先从我们的三维情况入手
and take a cross-section through this white plane
取这个包含了
that contains the camera and the viewing direction.
相机和视向的截面
Notice too that the white plane
同样也注意到白色平面
intersects the image plane on the line,
和像平面交于一条线
which we'll call the image line.
这条线将被称为相直线
That means if we draw just what's in the white plane,
这意味着如果我们仅画出落在白色平面上的东西
we get a picture like this.
我们就会得到如下的图片
To make the problem even easier,
为了更加简化这个问题
we'll try first intersecting
我们将尝试首先和最简单
with the simplest object possible,
的物体最相交
the line segment.
一条线段
Here's our scene:
这就是我们的场景
Just a line segment connecting two points, A and B.
仅有一条线段连接着两个点 A 和 B
To render the scene,
如果要渲染这个场景
just as in three dimensions,
如同三维场景一样
we need to pick a location for our camera.
我们需要为我们的摄像机找一个落点
Call the camera point, C.
称摄像机点为 C
Next, we pick a viewing direction, shown here in red.
下一步 我们找一个视向 这里用红色表示
In three dimensions,
在三维中
the camera location and viewing direction
相机位置和视向
defines an image plane.
定义了相平面
but in two dimensions, it gives us an image line.
但在二维中 它仅给出了一条像直线
That's the line in which our image will be formed.
这条线就是我们的像将产生的地方
Now, let's pick a point, P, on the image line
现在让我们在像直线上选择一个点 P
to denote the pixel we want to determine the color of.
来代表我们想确定其颜色的像素
Recall that the ray tracer builds a ray from C through P
回忆起光线追踪会建立一条从 C 穿过 P
off into the scene.
直达场景的射线
We need a mathematical way to compute intersection points.
我们需要一个数学的方法来计算交点
Like this one, called 'I'.
比如这个 称为 I
To develop the math,
为了展开数学运算
we first introduce a coordinate system.
我们先建立一个坐标系统
The math we need comes from looking at the Algebra
我们所需要的数学来自于
of intersecting a ray with a line segment.
计算射线和线段相交的代数方法
We've introduced quite a few ideas in this video.
我们在这个视频里介绍了不少想法
So, use the next exercise
所以 用下一个练习
to make sure you're comfortable
让你对二维光线追踪
with two-dimensional ray tracing. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
更熟悉一点吧 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox